raccars.co.uk 2017-06-06

# RAC Cars Privacy policy

This Privacy Policy explains how we use the information we collect about you, how you can instruct us if you prefer to limit the use of that information and the procedures we have put in place to safeguard your privacy. Please read it carefully.

## Who we are

For the purpose of the Data Protection Act 1998 ("Act"), the data controller is RAC Motoring Services (Company Number01424399) ("RAC"). The data processor is Motors.co.uk Limited (company number 05975777) (“Motors” )

## The information we collect

The information below provides an overview of how we protect your privacy whenever you are on this site. We may collect information about you in two ways: indirectly (for example, through cookies see section "Our Use of IP Addresses and Cookies") and/or directly for example:

Information you provide by filling in forms on our site;

If you contact us, we may keep a record of that correspondence.

Details of transactions you carry out through our site.

We may ask you for information when you report a problem with our site.

Throughout our site, we provide opportunities for you to apply for various products and services for example car data checks and car finance. Where information in response to a question is stated to be mandatory, we will not be able to process your application without that information. Where information in response to question is voluntary it is completely up to you whether or not you want to provide any information which is stated to be voluntary.

## How we use the information

We use information held about you in the following ways:

To provide you with a product or service or to enable a third party to provide you with a product or service you have requested.

To process any applications or requests for products or services you make to us or via us to a third party.

To ensure that the content on our site is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer.

To provide you with information, products or services that you request from us or, where you have consented to be contacted for such purpose, which we feel may interest you.

To notify you about changes to our service.

To notify you about special features on our site.

To aggregate information and statistics for the purpose of monitoring website usage in order to help us develop our site and our services. RAC may provide such aggregate information to third parties, such as advertisers to enable them to assess the value of advertising on our site, however the statistics will not include information that can be used to identify any individual.

To help us to make credit decisions about you, to prevent fraud, to check your identity and to prevent money laundering, we may search the files of credit reference agencies who will record any credit searches on your file. We may also disclose details of how you conduct any account to such agencies. The information will be used by other credit grantors for making credit decisions about you and the people with whom you are financially associated, for fraud prevention, money laundering prevention and occasionally for tracing debtors.

We may also use your data to provide you with information about services or products or related information which may be of interest to you and we or they may contact you about these by post, e-mail or telephone. 

Please note that your initial call to a dealer advertising a car for sale on this site may be monitored or recorded for quality and verification purposes.

If you are an existing customer, we will only contact you by electronic means (email or SMS) with information about services or products similar to those which were the subject of a previous supply to you via our site.

If you are a new customer we will contact you by electronic means only if you have consented to this.

If you do not want us to use your data in this way, or to pass your details on to selected third parties for marketing purposes, please tick the relevant box situated on the form on which we collect your data (the registration form).

## Your information shared

Information about our customers is an important part of our business. We share customer information only as described in this privacy policy.

## Businesses we do not control

Our site features the products and services of third party providers. Where a product or service is to be provided by a third party, for example motor loans, warranties, insurance, car data checks and valuations of your car, your information will be shared with that third party for purposes of delivering that product or service to you.

You will be able to tell when a third party is involved in your transactions and your personal information is shared and, before you submit any information, you will be notified and then it is up to you whether or not you want to provide it.

Where you purchase products or services from or provide information to a third party or access another website through our site, use of any information collected is subject to the privacy policy of the operator of the website you are visiting or the provider of such products or services you are purchasing. We have no control over those other websites or providers and are not responsible or liable for the privacy policies of the operators of those other websites or providers. This privacy policy applies solely to information collected on our site. Please check the privacy policies of operators of other websites or providers before you submit any personal data to those websites or providers. They may differ from ours. If you cannot find any privacy policy and require more information, please contact the provider directly.

## Disclosure of your information

If the RAC business is sold or integrated with another business, we may disclose your personal information to our advisers and any prospective purchasers and their advisers and such personal information will be passed on to the new owners of the business.

We may share your information where required in compliance with any legal obligation or to protect the rights, property or safety of RAC , our customers or others or our site or to enforce the terms of use of our site.

## Our use of IP addresses and cookies

We may collect information about your computer, including (where available) your IP address, operating system and browser type, for system administration, statistical analysis and to report aggregate information (which does not identify any individual) to our advertisers.

For the same reason we may obtain information about your general internet usage by using a cookie. Cookies are small text files placed on your hard drive each time you access a website. We may use cookies to facilitate your internet sessions, to maintain security and to improve our site. In particular, cookies enable us:

To estimate our audience size and usage pattern.

To store information about your preferences, and so allow us to customise our site according to your individual interests.

To speed up your searches.

To recognise you when you return to our site.

You can disable cookies on your computer by changing the settings in preferences or options in your menu browser. However, if you disable cookies you may be unable to access certain parts of our site. Unless you have adjusted your browser setting so that it will refuse cookies, our system will issue cookies when you log on to our site.

Please note that third party providers and our advertisers may also use cookies, over which we have no control.

## How we protect your information

Unfortunately the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. The open nature of the Internet is such that data may flow over networks without security measures and may be accessed and used by people other than those for whom the data is intended. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your personal data transmitted to our site; any transmission is at your own risk. However, we aim to apply appropriate levels of security at all times.

## Third party consent

If you give us information about another person (e.g. a joint applicant for a product or service), you confirm that the other person has appointed you to act on his/her behalf and has agreed that you are authorised to:

give consent on his/her behalf to the processing of his/her personal data (including any sensitive personal data) in accordance with this privacy policy; and

link or record information about him/her with you at credit reference agencies.

## Your rights

You are entitled to know whether we hold information about you and, if we do, you are entitled to have access to that information in accordance with the Act and to require it to be corrected if it is inaccurate. You can do this by contacting us by e-mail at [info@raccars.co.uk](mailto:info@raccars.co.uk). Any access request may be subject to a fee of £10 to meet our costs in providing you with details of the information we hold about you.

## Marketing to Children

RAC does not knowingly collect data from nor market to children anywhere.

## Your Consent

By submitting your information to us, you consent to the use of that information as set out in this privacy policy. If we change our privacy policy we will post the changes on this page, and may place notices on other pages of the website so that you may be aware of the information we collect and how it is used at all times. Where appropriate we will also notify you by e-mail. Continued use of our site will signify that you agree to any such changes.

## How to contact us

We welcome your views about our site and our privacy policy. If you would like to contact us with any queries, comments or requests please send an e-mail to [info@raccars.co.uk](mailto:info@raccars.co.uk)
